<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ziqqurratum</title>
    <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ziqqurratum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Iris Nikolova</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 14:26:28 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziqqurratum.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Current</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/current/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 15:07:26 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/current/</guid>
      <description>This is a fun idea a friend of mine showed me&amp;ndash;instead of posting random stuff at random times, just write what I&amp;rsquo;m doing at the moment here.&#xA;Media Music Glass Beach Laibach (preparing for concert on 16.10) Obraten Efekt (still hyped from concert on 27.07) Series House of the Dragon (soon™) Production ziqqurratum.com Short-Term Goals Furnish my wardrobe for the autumn/winter season Win the fight with my insurance (You ask to pay them more and you still have to fight them on it (ノಠ益ಠ)ノ彡┻━┻ ) What I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for/happy about Got my prescription finally, so now I can feel secure in having my meds available Did a lot of stuff over the past month of summer, and I feel very productive thanks to it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun idea a friend of mine showed me&ndash;instead of posting random stuff at random times, just write what I&rsquo;m doing at the moment here.</p>
<h2 id="media">Media</h2>
<ul>
<li>Music
<ul>
<li>Glass Beach</li>
<li>Laibach (preparing for concert on 16.10)</li>
<li>Obraten Efekt (still hyped from concert on 27.07)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Series
<ul>
<li>House of the Dragon (soon™)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="production">Production</h2>
<ul>
<li>ziqqurratum.com</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="short-term-goals">Short-Term Goals</h2>
<ul>
<li>Furnish my wardrobe for the autumn/winter season</li>
<li>Win the fight with my insurance (You ask to pay them more and you still have to fight them on it (ノಠ益ಠ)ノ彡┻━┻ )</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="what-im-grateful-forhappy-about">What I&rsquo;m grateful for/happy about</h2>
<ul>
<li>Got my prescription finally, so now I can feel secure in having my meds available</li>
<li>Did a lot of stuff over the past month of summer, and I feel very productive thanks to it.</li>
<li>I can observe/potentially pet my cat while I&rsquo;m still in Bulgaria</li>
</ul>
<p>If y&rsquo;all have any ideas for what else I can put here, or if you have recommendations for things I oughtta try/see/do, feel free to contact me about it))</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Маци</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/maci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 11:32:19 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/maci/</guid>
      <description>Мачки мачкат пръчки, правят съчки&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Мачки мачкат пръчки, правят съчки.<br>
&ldquo;Кажѝ, маци, защо с&rsquo;ти тез разбити ръчки&rdquo;<br>
Мило мяуна малка маца, каза &ldquo;тралала!<br>
въпроси не задавай. лягай, пръчките са за това!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Котето грациозно и важно врътна опашка<br>
от задния си джоб извади заредена калашка<br>
спусака дръпна и по пода изпрашка патрона!<br>
&ldquo;Ай, коти, недей с лошо-ще ми уцелиш панталона!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Тогаз голямо маце горчиво изграчи &ldquo;Гадино!<br>
Прави забележки и ще те пратя на кино!&rdquo;<br>
Болшоят котак изтупа своя фрак и скочи<br>
и съ&rsquo; замах уви своя мустак и почна мляко да лочи.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Лягайте, пухели, лягайте, спете! Тези театри ги оставете!&rdquo;<br>
Щом ме чу, маца дебела ме грабна в коленете<br>
&ldquo;Кат те хвана не пускам нищо&rsquo;свен мойте нокти,<br>
каква ще ми нареждаш на мене пък ти?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Е, аз се пък вече изтощих от котешки закачки.<br>
Каза̀х им &ldquo;чао чао&rdquo; и за вечеря им оставих няколко пачки.<br>
Отидох на лекар, подир в библотека, и не ща ли - мойте мачки<br>
прибрали ми цели парите и вместо храна си взели играчки!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 10:25:50 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Who are you? What is this? I&amp;rsquo;m Iris, and this is my website. Since 2022, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Amsterdam and studied at the UvA. My interest are various and include everything from the subject of my studies (ancient history of the Mediterranean and Mesopotamia) to music, art, philosophy and tech. The best way to give you an idea of this site is via a Q&amp;amp;A.&#xA;What will I find here? All sorts of stuff, really.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="who-are-you-what-is-this">Who are you? What is this?</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;m Iris, and this is my website. Since 2022, I&rsquo;ve lived in Amsterdam and studied at the UvA. My interest are various and include everything from the subject of my studies (ancient history of the Mediterranean and Mesopotamia) to music, art, philosophy and tech. The best way to give you an idea of this site is via a Q&amp;A.</p>
<h2 id="what-will-i-find-here">What will I find here?</h2>
<p>All sorts of stuff, really. Whatever I&rsquo;m interested in writing or publishing, I&rsquo;ll publish, but I can make no guarantee about a consistent and laser-focused stream of content. You&rsquo;re free to subscribe to the RSS feed and read whatever catches your eye. To give you a vague idea, I&rsquo;m likely to upload my poetry/short stories, reviews of media, s.a. books, films, musical albums, <em><strong>maybe</strong></em> some philosophical ideas, &lsquo;<em>travelogues</em>&rsquo;, memoires and so on.</p>
<h2 id="how-often-will-you-post">How often will you post?</h2>
<p>Whenever I have time ¯\<em>(ツ)</em>/¯</p>
<h2 id="will-you-write-in-languages-other-than-english">Will you write in languages other than English?</h2>
<p>Generally, I&rsquo;d like to write in other languages as well. The website has a multilingual feature, but I doubt I&rsquo;ll have enough content in different languages to justify using it. Currently, I&rsquo;m trying to learn Russian, French, German and (although this one is barely worth consideration atm) Dutch, my studies include Latin, Koine and Akkadian, and I am fluent in Bulgarian besides English. Still, of these I&rsquo;d only feel confident writing in Bulgarian. Perhaps I&rsquo;ll upload some multilingual content, but don&rsquo;t count on it being a constant.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-a-ziqqurratum">What is a &ldquo;Ziqqurratum&rdquo;</h2>
<p>A kind of <em>pyramidal</em> structure, built by the ancient Mesopotamians on top of which temples were constructed.</p>
<p>If I come up with any other questions, I&rsquo;ll add them here)</p>
<h1 id="technical-information">Technical Information</h1>
<h2 id="how-is-this-side-made">How is this side made?</h2>
<p>ziqqurratum.com has its domain registered by <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/dns/what-is-cloudflare-registrar/">Cloudflare</a>, it&rsquo;s hosted on <a href="https://github.io">github pages</a>, and it&rsquo;s made with <a href="https://gohugo.io">HUGO</a> and the <a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-bearcub/">Bear Cub theme</a> (which I&rsquo;ve modded). It has exactly 1 bit of JS, and that&rsquo;s the &ldquo;Quack&rdquo; button in the navbar because I thought it&rsquo;d be amusing.</p>
<h2 id="what-data-do-you-collect">What data do you collect?</h2>
<p>As far as I know, nothing. It&rsquo;s possible github pages collects some kind of annonymized statistical data for site visitors, but I have no knowledge of how to check. For what it&rsquo;s worth, I don&rsquo;t particularly wish to collect any data or serve ads, and if I&rsquo;m ever to monitize this project, I&rsquo;d probably do it with a donation platform like Patreon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
