<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Iris Nikolova on Ziqqurratum</title>
    <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/authors/iris-nikolova/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iris Nikolova on Ziqqurratum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Iris Nikolova</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:43:37 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ziqqurratum.com/authors/iris-nikolova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a Stray</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/stray/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:43:37 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/stray/</guid>
      <description>The tides of time&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The tides of time will flatten down<br>
The edges of our ancient shores;<br>
And if we&rsquo;ve wit, to dust we&rsquo;ll whip<br>
All sharpened shards left on the floor.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rijswijkstraat 175, May 24</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/rijswijkstraat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:39:12 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/rijswijkstraat/</guid>
      <description>Three burning crosses&amp;ndash;spears, ablaze&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three burning crosses<br>
—spears, ablaze,<br>
pierce the supple flesh<br>
of the mucky<br>
earth beneath our quavery feet,<br>
cut through the blackened,<br>
greasy,<br>
slimy<br>
sludge—<br>
the firmament<br>
is cut, split<br>
by ever-burning blazes;<br>
the putrid scourge they lay upon us,<br>
rancid stench<br>
of smoke, and ash,<br>
&rsquo;s cremation of a spirit,<br>
dagger<br>
in an arid heart</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autohalt</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/autohalt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:38:05 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/autohalt/</guid>
      <description>Wer sitzt in dem Auto? Wer wartet so still?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wer sitzt in dem Auto?<br>
Wer wartet so still?</p>
<p>Wer denkt uber alles?<br>
Wer glaubt noch nichts?</p>
<p>Wer ist der Kleinste?<br>
Klein wie ein&rsquo; Maus?</p>
<p>Wer ist so groß<br>
zu sein Seele verlier&rsquo;n?</p>
<p>Wer hört nur sein&rsquo; Tränen<br>
und sieht nur sie noch?</p>
<p>Und wer hat vergessen<br>
was er war doch?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quiet evening fishing on the shore of Αχερων</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/acheron/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:21:52 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/acheron/</guid>
      <description>The herring swims right down the stream&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The herring swims<br>
right down the stream,<br>
and Søren goes to catch it.<br>
But, if he faints<br>
and dies in pain,<br>
will Father come to snatch him?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stargazing with the rats of Sloterdijk</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/stargazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:26:28 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/stargazing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;These thoughts, they haunt me, taunt me, daunt me, turn my day into a chore..</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The signs of God now mark the sky</em><br>
<em>And their beauty doth caress my eye</em></p>
<p>Yet, though I hear his ringing voice,<br>
Mine eyes forsake his sacred lore;<br>
Are wetted, glossy, glassy, absent joy&rsquo;s<br>
delightful light,<br>
or life&rsquo;s long &rsquo;n loud encore.<br>
These thoughts, they haunt me,<br>
taunt me, daunt me, turn my day into a chore.<br>
They key and lock me into stasis,<br>
turn my ill-begotten, rotten misery a lonesome bore!<br>
Each and every painful pace is paid for by a hefty fee<br>
for which the payment, Cherubs tell me, I could never bear afford.<br>
But if I sack&rsquo;d these sorry feelings, shed the shattered core of y&rsquo;ore,<br>
if I declared my soul insolvent, purged it of the debts of y&rsquo;ore,<br>
won&rsquo;t that ghastly maiden, Justice, cleanse me of my craven,<br>
illness-laden, my forsaken heart and core?<br>
And won&rsquo;t the fair and giving Godhead, which we in the stars observe,<br>
impart upon me what is fairly clearly needed, nay—deserved?<br>
Resolutely, I am answered by a chanting from above:<br>
&ldquo;NAY!&rdquo; shout a thousand glowing faces,<br>
glowing faces up above, <br>
and they leave me kneeling, sobbing, scraping traces off the floor—<br>
scraping traces of their graces, lacking Destiny&rsquo;s rapport.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beef stock</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/</guid>
      <description>My name is Beef Stock, and I was born in Detroit in 1992, December 12 at 19:28 to be exact. I lived a peaceful, normal life for the first 14 months after my birth – I exercised outside regularly, I learned to urinate in the proper, designated place (that is to say, I was potty trained), and I learned to understand language rather well for a child my age. In fact, I was ahead of the curb in most things.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My name is Beef Stock, and I was born in Detroit in 1992, December 12 at 19:28 to be exact. I lived a peaceful, normal life for the first 14 months after my birth – I exercised outside regularly, I learned to urinate in the proper, designated place (that is to say, I was potty trained), and I learned to understand language rather well for a child my age. In fact, I was ahead of the curb in most things. From my first birthday I distinctly remember my adoptive mother patting me on the head softly and saying “Oh, you wonderful thing, I cannot believe how quickly you’ve adjusted to your new home.” She was right.</p>
<p>Sadly, this serene moment of my life would not last long after the first anniversary of my birth. In August of 1993 I was enlisted as a serviceman for the Zweite Alpiner Jägersessenkocher Regimet am Donau, and had to leave the peaceful residence of the Stocks in Vienna to pursue this career path thrust upon me. I would lie if I said I wasn’t homesick at times. I’d lie if I said it wasn’t most of the time. Yet, as is necessary for a young man, I adjusted well enough, and I was able to reach the level of Herdmuldeführer erste Band by the end of winter in March of 1994. Please do note that my statement from above was no exaggeration – I exceed in most things I undertake. This trait of mine is a blessing, but it also makes the next part of my story all the more tragic.</p>
<p>You see, summers in the Austrian alps tend to be less work for a logistics man such as myself – the lack of snow most weeks of July and August makes my personal skill in skis and sleds mostly useless to the regiment, and so I tend to rest up during these months and focus on my hobbies, such as language acquisition and yoga. During one especially unbearable day in August of 1996, in the prime of my life, I was called to a special operation near mt. Gotteszehsspitze by the little-known Keinecanneloninurskaiserschmarrnfluss tributary to the Danube. The temperature was an unprecedented 296,15 degrees Kelvin, the summer grasses were tall and my allergies were killing me.</p>
<p>My assignment was simple – rescue a lost seagull from Slovenia which must have forgot to charge its compass or otherwise been carried here by a malicious plane from Ljubljana. I have done this before, of course, and to great success at that, but it usually happens in winter while the seagulls are hibernating and are easier prey for kidnappers. Never mind, I was not about to lose my path to Pfannenfeldherrhelfer sechste Band. In order to reach the summit, I would have to carry 51 troy pounds of equipment on a snow sled, as the grass sleds had been taken out hours earlier by my colleagues for a Geheime Bierübernahme (mit Pretzel).</p>
<p>The trek was miserable – horse flies bit my nose as I dragged my burden through the tall, green, alpine grass. My sweat poured out like the juice at the bottom of the plate of fresh krautsalat. I almost shed a tear. Despite these challenges, I remained indefatigable, and I reached the mountain peak in only 1,73 decimal hours; a seagull was, indeed, awaiting assistance on the scorching rocks. One had to wonder how it was so distressed considering the abominable heat that must have surely reminded it of its tropical homeland in the former Yugoslav plains.</p>
<p>I unpacked my Feldausrüstung “Petite gastronomie pour les soldats petits,” and began tending to the bird. Although I was well-versed in the Edrine dialect of Bulgarian and in the beautiful Russian of Tomsk, I was not so privy to the intricacies and peculiarities of Serbo-Corato-Bosno-Herzegovino- Kosovarsko-Montenegrin; as such, despite my best efforts of combining Polish catholic funerary incantations and the most popular verses of the Albanian Poetic Edda, my communications with the gull were a resolute failure.</p>
<p>Despite this, and thanks to my commendable efforts and impressive experience, I succeeded in revitalizing the bird, and I made it my task to return to an air-conditioned space as soon as possible. I loaded my equipment and the seagull onto my sled and began my descent. As I approached the water in the valley below the mount, I was behest by a vision of a fair maiden drowning. My duty has always been to assist those in need, so I jumped into the river without thinking, and I tried to swim after the lady, but I had forgotten a crucial detail – my sled was still anchored to my now quickly sinking body.</p>
<p>Together with my sled and seagull I was dragged down into the danubian mainstream. Besides causing me to lose my status and identity as an alternative figure in the alpine community, this tragic event has also left me clinging to a thin rope at the edge of a cliff in the Hungarian part of the Pannonian basin. The gull remembered its nature a short time after falling into the water and managed to trace the river to Romania from where he presumably took a second class sleeping car or a cheap airliner to Ljubljana. Alas, my nature has always been that of a steadfast and grounded man, so I could not channel any fidelity in waterway navigation.</p>
<p>Now, as I hang at the edge of my rope, being held up by a sled’s lead, I write out my last will. If you find this document, tell my life story, preferably in the form of a hard-cover, leather-bound novella to be sold in all European markets and exported at a premium to the Chinese and Americans. Perhaps a commemorative statue in my birth town of Detroit would be a fair supplement to the book. Of course, I never visited after my adoption by the Stock family, but a bronze and granite memorial would allow me to remain there in spirit – an ever-valuable member of rust belt society, always ready to pick iron in the mines. I assume that’s what the rust belt does. Perhaps the inscription ought to read “perished of the black lung in service of the motherland.” I would like that.</p>
<p>Finally, I fold this note into a crane and leave it to float majestically on the waves of this deadly river, which falls next to me. May it reach you in good health and with appropriate speed so that you may, if not rescue me, at least execute the will I have submitted herein.</p>
<p>I confirm I am in sound mind, and sign this holographic document to be legally submitted to and enacted as law by the Österreichisches Parlament.</p>
<p>Signed, 6 August 1996</p>
<p>Beef Stock esq.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Маци</title>
      <link>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/maci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 11:32:19 +0300</pubDate><author>mail@ziqqurratum.com (Iris Nikolova)</author>
      <guid>https://ziqqurratum.com/archive/maci/</guid>
      <description>Мачки мачкат пръчки, правят съчки&amp;hellip;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Мачки мачкат пръчки, правят съчки.<br>
&ldquo;Кажѝ, маци, защо с&rsquo;ти тез разбити ръчки&rdquo;<br>
Мило мяуна малка маца, каза &ldquo;тралала!<br>
въпроси не задавай. лягай, пръчките са за това!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Котето грациозно и важно врътна опашка<br>
от задния си джоб извади заредена калашка<br>
спусъка дръпна и по пода изпрашка патрона!<br>
&ldquo;Ай, коти, недей с лошо-ще ми уцелиш панталона!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Тогаз голямо маце горчиво изграчи &ldquo;Гадино!<br>
Прави забележки и ще те пратя на кино!&rdquo;<br>
Болшоят котак изтупа своя фрак и скочи<br>
и съ&rsquo; замах уви своя мустак и почна мляко да лочи.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Лягайте, пухели, лягайте, спете! Тези театри ги оставете!&rdquo;<br>
Щом ме чу, маца дебела ме грабна в коленете<br>
&ldquo;Кат те хвана не пускам нищо&rsquo;свен мойте нокти,<br>
каква ще ми нареждаш на мене пък ти?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Е, аз се пък вече изтощих от котешки закачки.<br>
Каза̀х им &ldquo;чао чао&rdquo; и за вечеря им оставих няколко пачки.<br>
Отидох на лекар, подир в библотека, и не ща ли - мойте мачки<br>
прибрали ми цели парите и вместо храна си взели играчки!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
